Desmond Oghanihun Ugegeh

I am an ICT specialist willing to contribute towards the attainment of corporate vision and goal of organization that recognizes talent and professionalism as prerequisite for a sustainable competitive advantage in business.

Interest: A Data Scientist, a Researcher and a Cybersecurity specialist with special interest in Ethical Hacking and Python Programming.

Location: 1, Liberation Close, Off Nnebisi Road, Asaba.

State of Origin: Delta State

Email: desmondugegeh@gmail.com
Phone Contact: +234706 248 8322
linkedin.com/in/desmond-ugegeh-176a03a0

Personal Details

Date of Birth: 1990-09-25

Highest Level of Education: Master's

Industry: Analytics, Education & Instruction, IT Operations & Helpdesk, Information Technology, Media & Communications, Scientific Research & Development, Software

Development

NYSC Status: Completed

Work Experience

Web Development, Python Programming, Data Analysis and Cyber Security Instructor

ANN NOTCH DIGITAL ACADEMY, ASABA. May 2024 to Present

Cyber Security and Data Analysis Tutor

FHOBS SOLUTIONS, ASABA. - Asaba

February 2024 to Present

Adjunct Lecturer

University of Delta, Agbor - Agbor July 2023 to Present

Cyber Security Tutor

Asaba

September 2023 to November 2023

ICT Support Staff

SIP INFOTECH INSTITUTE - Ile-Ife, Osun April 2014 to May 2014

Monitoring and management of IT equipments

Education

Doctor of Philosophy in Science

Delta State University, Abraka, Delta State. - Abraka January 2024 to Present

Certificate in Data Analysis

TECH4DEV/NITDA/Digital for all Challenge 2024

Certificate in Software Development

TECH4DEV/NITDA/Digital for all Challenge 2024

Certificate in Basic Statistics with Python

DEPARTMENT OF ICT (REPUBLIC OF PHILIPPINES) 2024

Certificate in Cyber security Essentials

Cisco Networking Academy 2024

Certificate in Introduction to Data Science

Cisco Networking Academy 2024

Certificate in Endpoint Security

CISCO NETWORKING ACADEMY 2024

Certificate in Ethical Hacking

CISCO NETWORKING ACADEMY 2024

Certificate in Network Defense

CISCO NETWORKING ACADEMY 2024

Certificate in Cyber Threat Management

CISCO NETWORKING ACADEMY 2024

Certificate in Networking Essentials

CISCO NETWORKING ACADEMY 2024

Certificate in Building Python Web Apps

DEPARTMENT OF ICT (REPUBLIC OF PHILIPPINES) 2024

Certificate in Python Programming for Intermediate Users

DEPARTMENT OF ICT (REPUBLIC OF PHILIPPINES) 2024

Certificate in Data Analysis with Python

DEPARTMENT OF ICT (REPUBLIC OF PHILIPPINES) 2024

Certificate in Statistical Methods for Decision Making

Great Learning Academy - Bengaluru, Karnataka 2023

Certificate in Introduction to Ethical Hacking

Great Learning Academy - Bengaluru, Karnataka 2023

Certificate in Cyber security

EMMI/MICROSOFT/TECH4DEV - Asaba 2022

Master of Science

University of Lagos - Lagos February 2018 to March 2019

Post Graduate Diploma in EDUCATION

NATIONAL TEACHER'S INSTITUTE KADUNA - Lagos January 2016 to March 2017

Bachelors of Science Nnamdi Azikiwe University - Awka September 2008 to August 2012

Skills

- Excel (10+ years)
- Web Development (1 year)
- Problem solving (10+ years)
- Time management (10+ years)
- Cyber security (1 year)
- Ethical Hacking (1 year)
- Data Analysis (10+ years)
- Python Programming (1 year)

Additional Information

Professional Skills:

- Excellent IT skills, skilled and proficient to work on varied kinds of Microsoft packages such as MS- Excel and other MS-Office software s to enter access or retrieve data.
- Proficiency in Data Analysis using Excel, SPSS and Python Programming.
- Excellent understanding of Cyber security, Information Security, Data Protection and Management.
- Basic understanding of HTML/CSS programming language.
- Project Management Skills.
- Effective communication skills (verbal and written).
- Strong people management skill.